<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | Klem Research Group</title>
    <link>Klem-Research-Group.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="Klem-Research-Group.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>Klem-Research-Group.github.io/media/icon_hu_4f30228ebcdcf26c.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>Klem-Research-Group.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klem Lab Hiring Postdoctoral Researcher for Fall 2025</title>
      <link>Klem-Research-Group.github.io/post/2025-06-05-postdoc-hiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>Klem-Research-Group.github.io/post/2025-06-05-postdoc-hiring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Klem Research Group at Louisiana State University is actively recruiting a &lt;strong&gt;postdoctoral researcher&lt;/strong&gt; to join the lab in &lt;strong&gt;Fall 2025&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our group focuses on &lt;strong&gt;computational enzymology&lt;/strong&gt;, developing integrative workflows that combine quantum mechanics, molecular dynamics, and machine learning to understand and engineer enzyme function. We are particularly interested in applicants with experience in &lt;strong&gt;biomolecular modeling, method development, or enzymatic mechanism studies&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This position offers the opportunity to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lead and co-author high-impact research on topics such as antibiotic resistance and plastic degradation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contribute to open-source tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://qmzyme.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;QMzyme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate with experimental and computational researchers at LSU and internationally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The position is fully funded and offers a supportive, collaborative, and highly interdisciplinary environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, please contact Dr. Heidi Klem directly with your CV and a brief cover letter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔁 &lt;strong&gt;Please share with colleagues and students who may be interested!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Klem Lab Officially Launches at LSU</title>
      <link>Klem-Research-Group.github.io/post/05-05-2025-klem-lab-launch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>Klem-Research-Group.github.io/post/05-05-2025-klem-lab-launch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Klem Research Group will open its doors this Fall 2025 at Louisiana State University! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab focuses on integrative computational modeling of enzymes to address critical challenges in medicine and sustainability, including antibiotic resistance and plastic degradation. We&amp;rsquo;re building tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://qmzyme.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;QMzyme&lt;/a&gt; to make quantum enzymology more accessible, and we’re excited to kick off collaborations, software development, and new research directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in joining the team or learning more about our work, visit the &lt;a href=&#34;Klem-Research-Group.github.io/join&#34;&gt;Join&lt;/a&gt; page or check out our &lt;a href=&#34;Klem-Research-Group.github.io/research&#34;&gt;Research&lt;/a&gt; areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned — we have exciting updates ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
